<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>How to Make Stuff</title>
 <link href="http://asor12.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://asor12.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2026-02-27T12:41:28-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://asor12.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>asor12</name>
   <email>op.3no.2@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>What would a remote world look like?</title>
   <link href="http://asor12.github.io/old/2020/05/25/what-would-remote-world-look-like.html"/>
   <updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://asor12.github.io/old/2020/05/25/what-would-remote-world-look-like</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-would-a-remote-world-look-like&quot;&gt;What would a remote world look like?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;5.25.20 - San Francisco - R. Lin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crystal ball, the future is in your gaze, coalesce your vision for me in that effervescent glaze. What thoughts hide behind that dome? What more do your gentle threads bode? Come bring me the future if all humankind worked from home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t expect all humankind to work from home, but what might happen if a significant chunk of knowledge workers did so? I’ve done so the last two years while running a startup, so I have some first-hand experience. Here are my thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-10-possibilities&quot;&gt;List of 10 possibilities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home matters much more.&lt;/strong&gt; Your roommates matter more, you need more space, you need a home workstation(s). Some people may shift back to the ‘burbs and/or live closer to family.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;1a. Businesses close by residential areas will see more demand, which may spur businesses to go there. But, that will be capped by a rise in cloud models (delivery-first businesses). The main bottleneck to cloud services will be delivery (tech enabling faster, cheaper, automated delivery will help).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;1b. There will be a shift to houses vs. apartments. At least, at first before apartments figure out their location is less of/no longer a selling feature. Then, apartments will evolve by offering more amenities (normal apartments will need to start looking like luxury apts).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salaries will level out.&lt;/strong&gt; When companies can choose from anyone, provided they have language and cultural fit, they will offer fewer Bay area salaries and bump the pay of cheaper locales. This will also drive bigger profits for companies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone will need more cleaning services.&lt;/strong&gt; People can’t spend their workday running the dishwasher and cleaning up after cooking. Companies will need to provide perks for this if people are going to work remote long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diffusion.&lt;/strong&gt; As Bay area tech companies are the first to go remote, techies will spread out to other cities (Denver, Austin, Hawaii). Not everyone will go, but there will be some diffusion. This will cause Bay area real estate/rental prices to go down. But, people will realize that they like living next to similar people - e.g. startups will want to move to a city other startups are at too. So, it will raise demand for certain other locales. The main points will be time zone, standard of living to price, where other techies are.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business travel will go down&lt;/strong&gt; (many ppl have said this). We started out our company traveling to different cities visiting prospective customers. It is nice to meet people in person, but we didn’t land any of our customers this way. We landed our first customers after we realized it wasn’t necessary to meet people in person, video calls work too - and was a lot cheaper. Will personal travel go up? I don’t know. Maybe being a digital nomad - living and working from different places - will go up instead.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People will go out less.&lt;/strong&gt; This happens if you live with your friends, and you spend your socializing at home. Related to #1, home amenities will be more important. Maybe people like pools, saunas at home. Extra living spaces will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Perhaps people will go out more at first, to get their socializing in while living in their current space. But as leases come up, more people will ask why not live with a group of friends. Or, move as a group into an apartment building (or to a block of houses) so you get private space and friends nearby. People already did this before, but more people will seek it when work doesn’t serve their social needs as much.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech companies realize that people need some in-person time.&lt;/strong&gt; Completely remote works well for tech-heavy companies - programmers work well alone. But creative and team efforts will be hampered by being remote.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People will shift ways to meet new people in person.&lt;/strong&gt; Work and school have been major ways people meet each other. Where people live will become how people meet each other.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downtown will get emptied.&lt;/strong&gt; Perhaps it will be transformed into living space. But, without the draw of work, there will be no reason for people to live near office buildings. People will move to spaces with more space, more green, more local businesses, more outdoor recreation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cities will have to be more competitive&lt;/strong&gt; to retain residents. They can’t let crime, filth fester because people can move away now. They aren’t tied to a locale by work/in-person meetings. Companies have more choice where to locate smaller HQs (and where to pay taxes).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;being-in-person-drove-density&quot;&gt;Being in-person drove density&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, being in-person drove density. People needed to be (reasonably) close to their work, which also drove restaurants, shopping, entertainment to be close to all that. If people don’t need to be close to their work, restaurants, shopping, entertainment will shift to where they live. People still like being around others, but there will be more diffusion as people no longer have to be crammed in close quarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Furthermore, the rise of on-demand delivery will mean even more diffusion.&lt;/strong&gt; Now people don’t even need to be near lots of shopping, groceries, etc. The main bottleneck will be on-demand delivery methods. Automated drones/vehicles would help this a lot, if they can get over politics. Maybe the tech will move to locales that allow this, and people will follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, people like public spaces. They like strolling through a vibrant community center with restaurants, arts, and entertainment. But people gravitate to the lowest energy orbit. Maybe this means more mobile restaurants and entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonus-predictions-from-the-crystal-ball&quot;&gt;Bonus predictions from the crystal ball&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More free time, more hobbies.&lt;/strong&gt;  People now have 1-2 more free hours in the day without commutes. They’ll want to find things to do with that time, with reading, hobbies, socializing, exercising, games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People will be farther, but also more inescapable.&lt;/strong&gt; This will extend what happened when people got cell phones, then social media. More people remote means less social barriers to asking to hang out. Now there’s less excuse to turn down a video call, when you’re not even being asked to dress up and go out! People will need a “silent mode” for their time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social circles might shrink for some and widen for others.&lt;/strong&gt; This depends on how much home/leisure replaces work for meeting new people. If you have a good home/leisure engine for meeting new people, you will both meet more people and get to know them better/faster. If you don’t, you will spend more time with people you already know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies will have issues with culture.&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing a remote culture is harder than in person. People will have less loyalty. On the flip side, there will be less politics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;services-for-a-work-from-home-population&quot;&gt;Services for a work-from-home population&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some ideas for services/products geared for a work-from-home crowd:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More casual wear - jeans, tennis shoes, sandals, athleisure. Less formal wear. Less makeup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More reading/newsletters/blogs/books/essays. Tools to help consume and produce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social living places. Groups that organize social events for a building/block/other community. Residences that provide living space, activities, and work setups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More outdoor equipment, products, services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More crafts, hobbies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More cooking services/products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brokers helping US tech firms find top talent in other countries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom video call backgrounds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AR for video calls (Why share your screen when you can write/draw/share directly on the video?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Sell</title>
   <link href="http://asor12.github.io/old/2020/03/26/how-to-sell.html"/>
   <updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://asor12.github.io/old/2020/03/26/how-to-sell</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-sell&quot;&gt;How to Sell&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;3.26.20 - San Francisco - R. Lin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, about two years ago, as I embarked on this startup journey, I was a green sprout with nary a sale to my name, completely naive and unencumbered as to what enterprise constituted, what was a funnel, how to lead a discovery call, what it meant to qualify, how to close a deal. Like many technical folks out there who all their lives thought to let the result, the product, the art speak for itself, I had no experience in having to chase down people and ask them to part with money. And while letting the product speak for itself can work to some extent in consumer-facing sales, it’s quite another in business-facing deals (aka business-to-business, B2B sales).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while there is still much to learn and experience, to try and to rail and to win, let me do my bit to pass on what wisdom I’ve accumulated these past two years to you, fellow internet reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sales&quot;&gt;Sales&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales is a whole discipline unto itself. There is actually quite a lot of terminology and practice that goes in it. But if you had to learn one thing, one thing that carries you through many deals, like a small, simple pocket-knife sufficient for opening most things, it is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;block&quot;&gt;
1. Ask questions
&lt;br /&gt;
2. Shut up and listen
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(That might appear to be two things, but it’s only so because some people erroneously do one without the other.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-questions&quot;&gt;Ask questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask questions. What kind? you might ask. It doesn’t matter. Start with some softball questions. How’s their day going? Where are they located? What’s the weather like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now briefly (briefly!) introduce yourself. Two sentences. Now ask them questions again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What problem do they have? How big of a problem is it? How are they dealing with it? How many people does it require?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have they tried so far? Why is it such a problem? Did they try X?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What solutions are they looking at? What’s their budget? Who determines their budget? How do they evaluate solutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s their timeline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shut-up-and-listen&quot;&gt;Shut up and listen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal now is to get them to talk as much as possible, to open up to you. The more they open up to you, the more they build trust that you’ll listen and hear them, that you might actually be able to fix their problem because you understand. So shut up and listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many new startup founders talk too much when they’re trying to sell something. I know, because I did this. You’re trying to explain how you work, how great you’d do to tackle their problem, all the ways you’re different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waltzed into my first big enterprise sales meeting at a huge, world-renowned firm, conference table lined with high-level managers and decision makers. I got this meeting because I used to work there and had left to start my business. We already had a small contract with them. I was now pitching them on a organization-wide deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then proceeded to talk, probably about 90% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, they shook my hand and said how impressed they were, and asked about my travel plans. I listed other impressive firms we were visiting. Oh wow, they said. They all shook my hand again and waved me goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did we get that deal? Did we get any of the other leads on our trip?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you know the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned to ask questions and shut up.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;now-that-youve-asked-questions-and-shut-up-what-next&quot;&gt;Now that you’ve asked questions, and shut up, what next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It depends. Are they a potential customer? You asked questions for two reasons: 1) to get them to talk and 2) to see if you can solve their problem. Maybe it’s the case that you actually aren’t a good fit for their problem, now that you’ve heard it. In that case, tell them so, but ask to keep in touch. If you end up with a solution in the future, you can ping them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, it is likely that you’re just starting out. Like a lonely teen looking for a date, most everyone looks attractive. In which case, get a second date! Take the rein, say, “This sounds like it could be a good fit. For next steps, let’s [fill in what you’ll like to do].”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appropriate second date options: running a trial/asking them for data to test with/getting a second meeting with more people/something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll likely need several meetings before you can land the deal. The bigger the organization, the more meetings, the longer it will take. It can take anywhere from a few weeks to 12+ months. Buckle up for the slow ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The likelihood of you landing any one deal is not high, so you’ll need to be running several deal processes at once. This is your “funnel”. You start out with a large number of prospects. Then you “qualify” them to make sure they’re a good fit for your product/ service/solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the remaining, you’ll move to next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate, here’s an example with a strapping teen, Mustafah, selling something we can all relate to - himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mustafahs-funnel&quot;&gt;Mustafah’s funnel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mustafah, 17, is looking for a girlfriend. He’s learned how to drive, so he can offer rides, his lanky frame, and weekend video game sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;block&quot;&gt;
Prospects - 50 girls in a 15-mile radius. → Mustafah&apos;s move: Text them all &lt;br /&gt;

First cut - 20 girls willing to date a teenager. → Mustafah&apos;s move: Ask them for a call &lt;br /&gt;

Second cut - 10 girls actually willing to talk. → Mustafah&apos;s move: Call them &lt;br /&gt;

Third cut - 5 girls who actually pick up the phone. → Mustafah&apos;s move: Talk to them &lt;br /&gt;

Fourth cut - 3 girls willing to go on a date.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; → Mustafah&apos;s move: Arrange dates&lt;br /&gt;

Fifth cut - 2 girls who liked their date enough to go on a second one. → Mustafah&apos;s move: Arrange second date &lt;br /&gt;

Sixth cut - 1 girl who likes their second date enough to go on a third one. → Mustafah&apos;s move: Arrange a third date, and make it so good she wants to go steady. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if the lone remaining girl doesn’t like her third date enough to go steady? you might ask. Well, that’s a risk. To mitigate this risk, Mustafah might consider broadening his funnel. Maybe he looks for ladies in a 30-mile radius, so he increases his top-of-funnel numbers. Though, he wouldn’t want to go too far, otherwise he’ll be stretched too thin and also be perceived as spamming the girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you’ll get lucky, and you land the first lead you talk to. Other times, you might have to talk to dozens before you land a deal. In any case, if you want to land multiple deals on an ongoing basis, you’ll have to implement a funnel to ensure your chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is illustrative for you, and helps you make sales of your own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; There are a few times when you get to go on a spiel. That’s 1) when the prospect asks you questions and 2) after you’ve let them talk a lot. And even then, don’t talk more than necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; One girl says she’ll only date guys who know how to crochet. Mustafah doesn’t know how to crochet. Should he learn how to crochet? Depends on 1) How hard/long it’ll take him and 2) How many other options he has (who don’t require crocheting skills). In this case, Mustafah doesn’t have a lot of options, and despite having two left thumbs he negotiates to learn crocheting if it turns into a real relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leads will often request special things from you. Push back a little, see how much they need it. And if they insist, and it’s something you can do, say you’ll do it if you have a deal. That way you make sure they’re willing to make a trade, and not just running you around in circles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deploy an App to Kubernetes (Digital Ocean)</title>
   <link href="http://asor12.github.io/old/2020/03/25/deploy-app-kubernetes.html"/>
   <updated>2020-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://asor12.github.io/old/2020/03/25/deploy-app-kubernetes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;deploy-an-app-to-kubernetes-digital-ocean&quot;&gt;Deploy an App to Kubernetes (Digital Ocean)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;3.25.20 - San Francisco - R. Lin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might come upon you one day to host a rapidly scalable containerized app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you have an application with such byzantine requirements that you have little recourse but to Dockerize it. Perhaps you received a trunkload of free cloud credits from one of the hulks trying to swipe off their competition. Whatever your circumstances, here is a guide to a path forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-steps&quot;&gt;Pre-Steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, get yourself seated comfortably at a chair or perched at a standing desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, spin up a browser and make your way to the cloud provider of your choice. In this case, I am using Digital Ocean. &lt;em&gt;If you are using something else, do not despair, I’m sure there are many nifty guides out there. Unless if you are using AWS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, before we move on, if you have a Dockerized app, deploy your app to DockerHub (you can choose a public or private repo). You will use &lt;em&gt;yourDockerUsername/project&lt;/em&gt; as your image in the yaml file below. (Instructions at end of post.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps-to-deployment&quot;&gt;Steps to Deployment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Login to Digital Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the Create button –&amp;gt; select Clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last! We are at the gates of Kubernetes. Follow the instructions for setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last step, marked ‘deploy the app’, do take a moment to check that your cluster is available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Terminal, run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl --context [insert-context-name-here] get nodes&lt;/code&gt;.  It should return your cluster(s).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To see your current context, run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl config current-context&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now create a deployment.yaml file in the root of your project folder with the following template code:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: v1
kind: Service
metadata:
  name: [name of your app]
spec:
  selector:
    app: [name of your app]
  ports:
  - protocol: &quot;TCP&quot;
    port: 6000
    targetPort: 5000
  type: LoadBalancer

---
apiVersion: apps/v1
kind: Deployment
metadata:
  name: [name of your app]
spec:
  selector:
    matchLabels:
      app: [name of your app]
  replicas: 2
  template:
    metadata:
      labels:
        app: [name of your app]
    spec:
      containers:
      - name: [name of your app]
        image: [yourDockerUsername/repoName]
        imagePullPolicy: Always
        ports:
        - containerPort: 5000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This YAML file tells Kubernetes what you want to run. It is telling Kubernetes the following: * Open the gates of port 6000 for this fine load-balanced service * Spin up two instances (‘Replicas’) of the container, so that if one fails ye shall have another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ImagePullPolicy: Always&lt;/code&gt; tells Kubernetes it should always pull the latest version of your image, but this can actually get a little tricky. If your image name/tag doesn’t change, it just ignores it. (More on that in Section ‘Updating’).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deploy-the-app&quot;&gt;Deploy the App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you are ready to unleash your app onto Kubernetes. Deploy the app with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl --context [your-context-name-here] apply -f deployment.yaml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re deploying from a private Dockerhub repo, create a Secret on Kubernetes (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.ibm.com/tutorials/accessing-dockerhub-repos-in-iks/&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that the pods deployed with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl get pods&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check if the service is ready with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl get service&lt;/code&gt; (This may take a few minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it’s ready, it’ll list an External-IP address, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NAME                 TYPE           CLUSTER-IP      EXTERNAL-IP       PORT(S)          AGE
mordor-test-api    LoadBalancer   XX.XXX.XXX.XX   XX.XXX.XXX.XX   80:32101/TCP     33m
isengard-test-api   LoadBalancer   XX.XXX.XXX.XX   XX.XXX.XXX.XX   6000:32206/TCP   5m19s
kubernetes           ClusterIP      XX.XXX.XXX.XX      &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;            443/TCP          57m
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the external IP address to see if your app is running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if your app is an API, call a request, say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;curl -X GET &quot;http://XX.XXX.XXX.XX:6000/api&quot; -H &quot;Content-Type: application/json&quot; --data &apos;{&quot;message&quot;: [&quot;this house is red&quot;]}&apos;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;→ This should return a response, like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{&quot;ESTIMATE&quot;:&quot;No&quot;}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lo and behold, if all has worked, you have a serviceable app running on Kubernetes. Pat thyself heartily for your efforts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-you-mess-up&quot;&gt;When You Mess Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you mess up anywhere, just delete your deployment and start over. &lt;em&gt;This might not be the proper way, but it works for me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl get all&lt;/code&gt; to list all applications and services on the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, delete the app’s Deployment and Service using kubectl delete: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl delete {name of deployment} {name of service}&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;for example, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl delete deployment.apps/mordor-test-api-deploy service/mordor-test-api-service&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;returns: deployment “simple-deployment” deleted&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;service “simple-service” deleted&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More here: 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://coreos.com/tectonic/docs/latest/tutorials/sandbox/deleting-deployment.html&quot;&gt;https://coreos.com/tectonic/docs/latest/tutorials/sandbox/deleting-deployment.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;updating&quot;&gt;Updating&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way I’ve found to update is to set the image to your latest version. You need to have tagged your image with a different tag, like v1/v2/vn etc. 
Run 
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl set image deployments/mordor-test-rosa-deploy mordor-api-container=op3no2/mordor-api:[version #]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the external IP to check that it updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I likely would not have set up my app on Kubernetes without the help of the following links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example app from Digital Ocean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/digitalocean/doks-example&quot;&gt;https://github.com/digitalocean/doks-example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/blog/2019/07/23/get-started-with-kubernetes-using-python/&quot;&gt;https://kubernetes.io/blog/2019/07/23/get-started-with-kubernetes-using-python/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploy private DockerHub to Kubernetes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.ibm.com/tutorials/accessing-dockerhub-repos-in-iks/&quot;&gt;https://developer.ibm.com/tutorials/accessing-dockerhub-repos-in-iks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploy ML model as an API on AWS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://towardsdatascience.com/deploy-a-machine-learning-model-as-an-api-on-aws-43e92d08d05b&quot;&gt;https://towardsdatascience.com/deploy-a-machine-learning-model-as-an-api-on-aws-43e92d08d05b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolling-update without downtime:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sebastian-daschner.com/entries/zero-downtime-updates-kubernetes&quot;&gt;https://blog.sebastian-daschner.com/entries/zero-downtime-updates-kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;docker-instructions&quot;&gt;Docker instructions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(After creating a dockerfile)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the app/ directory, run:
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker build -t &amp;lt;your-dockerhub-username&amp;gt;/model_api .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then run: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker run -p 5000:5000 &amp;lt;your-dockerhub-username&amp;gt;/model_api&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your application is now running in a Docker container. You can access it on http://XX.XXX.XXX.XX:5000/api or whatever port you set it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker push &amp;lt;your-dockerhub-username&amp;gt;/model_api&lt;/code&gt; to push the image to your DockerHub account.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
